Blake Stickland

Phone: +61 417 793 053 | Email: blakestickland@gmail.com | Melbourne, VIC, 3070

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/blake-stickland
Portfolio: https://blakestickland.github.io/react-portfolio
GitHub: https://github.com/blakestickland

Full-Stack Web Developer with a desire to utilise professional experience, background, and new web development skills as a Multimedia Programmer in the Arts. Recently earned a certificate for Full-Stack Web Development from the Monash University Coding Boot Camp. Creative result-focussed problem-solver passionate about user-experience informed design. Strengths in lateral approaches, teamwork and building fully-realised projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, NoSQL

Applications: GitHub, MySQL, MongoDB

Tools: Express, React, Node, Handlebars, Bootstrap, Materialize, Heroku, AJAX, Travis

PROJECTS

Rhythmic Machine | https://github.com/blakestickland/rhythmic-machine | https://dry-journey-82163.herokuapp.com/

- A simple mobile-friendly web-browser based drum machine that is capable of playing selectable rhythmic patterns to inspire the user.
- Patterns are stored on a cloud database and load when the website is accessed.
- Solo project using Joe Selfi's React-808, further developed by Rob Brennan, as a guide.
- MongoDB, Express, React and Node.js (ie. MERN), use-sound and classnames npm libraries, APIs, HTML, custom CSS developed by Joe Selfi, deployed to Heroku, mobile-friendly in landscape mode.

Well ♥ Me | https://github.com/blakestickland/project2 | https://lkblt-project2.herokuapp.com/

- An easy web-based way to track and reach fitness goals faster. Follows MVC design pattern; uses Sequelize as an ORM to query and route data in the app and Handlebars to generate the HTML.
- Co-developer in a group of five.
- JavaScript, Node.js, npm libraries, APIs, HTML, CSS, Heroku, Sequelize, passport, Foundation by Zurb, Handlebars,
- Chart displaying daily log data from the most recent week; recipe cards produced based on diet requirements.

EXPERIENCE

Venue Technical Support University of Melbourne

2019-Present Melbourne, VIC

Implement technical solutions for production and event goals to students and stakeholders. Key Accomplishments:

- Diagnose errors in student installations and train, motivate and inspire small student groups of up to 5 people to achieve efficient, result-conscious solutions.
- Reconcile evolving artistic outcomes with time management in collaboration with students and stakeholders to successfully achieve an outstanding event.

Technician 2014-Present Melbourne Recital Centre Melbourne, VIC

Engineer sound for concerts, recording sessions and livestreams in multiple spaces. Key Accomplishments:

- Operate and co-ordinate sound reinforced events in the 1000-seat capacity multi-performance venue as part of a team staging more than 550 events per year.
- Contribute daily to achieving time and budget-related goals for both venue and client
 which enabled the Centre to grow it's brand domestically and internationally, fostering
 strong relationships with touring artists and promoters.

AV Technician 2009-Present Federation Square (for AV contractor Creative Vision Audio) Melbourne, VIC

Contribute to the AV team through provision of sound for predominantly live events across the Federation Square site.

Key Accomplishments:

- Recognized by managers for professionalism in commitment to clients when dealing with unexpected circumstances.
- Consistently requested by management to operate high-profile events that demand attention to detail and an achievable approach to the job such as the opening event for the Melbourne International Arts Festival in 2017, 2018 and 2019.
- Excel in application to job regardless of audience size (which can range from 20 to 10,000 audience members depending on the event).

EDUCATION

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development – Monash University Melbourne, VIC

Bachelor of Arts (Honours) - La Trobe University Melbourne, VIC

INTERESTS

Max/MSP, Supercollider, Pro Tools, plug-ins, Electroacoustic music, Recording music